Haipeng Yu

CONTACT INFORMATION

A218C Animal Sciences Complex Department of Animal Sciences University of Nebraska-Lincoln Lincoln, NE 68583-0908 USA

E-mail: haipeng.yu@huskers.unl.edu

Phone: (701) 730-1368 WWW: haipengu.github.io

CAREER GOALS

My passion for agriculture led me to study Veterinary Medicine in my undergraduate. During those four years, I found my passion and interest in breeding and genetics, which led me to pursue graduate studies in that area. During my master study, I have become familiar with the breeding and genetics of beef cattle, and developed a great interest in quantitative genetics. After I got my Masters, I started pursuing a Ph.D. degree in quantitative genetics. My long-term goal is to become a quantitative geneticist, incorporate statistics and bioinformatics to explore and discover animal and plant breeding and genetics then apply these discoveries into daily practice to help improve the development of livestock and plant production.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, Nebraska USA Ph.D., Animal Science - Quantitative Genetics

August 2016 - Present

• Advisor: Dr. Gota Morota

North Dakota State University, Fargo, North Dakota USA

M.S., Animal Breeding and Genetics

August 2016

- Thesis: "The exploration of a four-platform standing scale in the application of measuring temperament in beef cattle"
- Advisor: Dr. Lauren Hulsman Hanna

Qingdao Agricultural University, Qingdao, Shandong CHINA

B.S., Veterinary Medicine

July 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, Nebraska USA Graduate Research Assistant

August 2016 - Present

North Dakota State University, Fargo, North Dakota USA Graduate Teaching Assistant

• ANSC 357 Animal Genetics

Spring 2016

• AGRI 189 Skills for Academic Success

Fall 2015

Graduate Research Assistant

01/2015 - 05/2016

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

• American Society of Animal Science, member.

01/01/2017 - 01/01/2019

PEER REVIEWED JOURNAL PAPERS

• Yu H, Spangler ML, Lewis RM, and Morota G. Genomic relatedness strengthens genetic connectedness across management units. G3: Genes, Genomes, Genetics. doi: 10.1534/g3.117.300151

PAPERS IN PROCEEDINGS

• Yu H, Spangler ML, Lewis RM, and Morota G. 2018. GitHub/HaipengU.github.io/CV/Stronger measures of genomic connectedness enhance prediction accuracies across management units In: *Proceedings, 11th World Congress of Genetics Applied to Livestock Production*. February 11-16, Auckland, New Zealand.

CONTRIBUTED PRESENTATIONS

- NCERA-225 Annual Meeting. Stronger measures of genomic connectedness enhance prediction accuracies across management units. Stanley Stout Livestock Marketing Center, Manhattan, KS. October 18-19, 2017.
- ASAS-CSAS Annual Meeting and Trade Show. Genomic Relatedness Strengthens Genetic Connectedness Across Management Units. Baltimore, MD. July 8-12, 2017.

CONFERENCES ATTENDED

- NCERA-225 Annual Meeting, North Dakota State University, ND, October 22-23, 2015.
- Graduate Learning Conference for College Teaching, North Dakota State University, ND, August 17-18, 2015.
- WERA-1: Beef Cattle Breeding in the Western Region, Miles City, MT, May 19-20, 2015.
- Midwest Meeting of American Society of Animal Science, Des Moines, IA, March 15-18, 2015.

INTRAMURAL SEMINARS

- Animal Breeding and Genetics seminar." Genomic relatedness strengthens genetic connectedness across management units". Department of Animal Science, University of Nebraska-Lincoln. February 14, 2017.
- Animal Breeding & Genetics Seminars. Department of Animal Sciences, University of Nebraska-Lincoln. September 29, 2016.
- M.S., Thesis Defense. Department of Animal Sciences, North Dakota State University. May 17, 2016.

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

- Introduction to Graphical Models With Applications to Quantitative Genetics and Genomics, Iowa State University, IA, June 19-23, 2017.
- Software Carpentry Workshop. University of Nebraska-Lincoln, NE, January 5-6, 2017.

HONORS/ AWARDS

- Frank Bain Graduate Student Scholarship, North Dakota State University, Spring 2015
- Excellent Student, Qingdao Agricultural University, China, 2009-2013

REFERENCES

- Dr. Gota Morota, Department of Animal Sciences, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, NE. *E-mail*: morota@unl.edu, *Phone*: (402) 472-6031
- Dr. Lauren Hulsman Hanna, Animal Science Department, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND. *E-mail*: Lauren.Hanna@ndsu.edu, *Phone*: (701) 231-7636